MARTIN ROSE, MBA

Aligning information technology with business needs to create innovative solutions that drive change

www.linkedin.com/in/MartinRoseCIO : 203.241.6945 : martinprose33@gmail.com

Progressive Information Technology Executive with over twenty years of achievement in developing Information Technology organizations and strategies which align to business goals and objectives. Strong turnaround leader who can transform an Information Technology organization into a business and customer centric solutions team. Experienced senior manager, business partner and stakeholder collaborator who can apply innovative technology concepts to drive improved business outcomes. Strong business acumen aligning business value with technology solutions. Ideal balance and diverse experience in leading highly skilled teams within complex private sector organizations and public sector governments.

Core Competencies

- Technology & Business Strategy
- Enterprise Resource Planning
- Program & Project Management
- -Innovation & Enterprise Architecture
- Applications & Software Development
- Customer Relationship Management
- Business Intelligence & Analytics
- Organization & Talent Development
- Infrastructure & Operations
- Information & Cyber Security
- Finance & Budget Management
- Vendor & Contract Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Seminole Tribe of Florida, Hollywood, FL.

Tribal Government serving the needs of Tribal Members

2017 - 2019

CHIEF INFORMATION OFFICER

Chosen to direct private sector Information Technology Organization providing public sector services. Rebuild and support all areas within Information Technology including Infrastructure Engineering, Security, Applications Development and Support, Operations, Project Management Office, Customer Relationship Management, Finance and Budgets. Supported the Information Technology needs of over forty verticals across seven reservations including Education, Public Safety, Community Development, Hospitality, Entertainment and Health Services. Partnered with Hard Rock International on technology needs.

- Align technology solutions to business unit strategic plans to create a 5 year technology/business strategic plan.
- Increase functionality of the Lawson Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) system to provide an enriched user experience for all modules including Finance, Accounting, Procurement, Payroll and Human Resources.
- Recognize enterprise wide improvements through the implementation of new custom and commercial business applications and enhancements to existing business applications increasing efficiency across all verticals.
- Decrease security risk 4X by acquiring staff, skills, tools and process required to support an enterprise security footprint.
- Adopt a Cloud first strategy incorporating commercial Cloud and Microsoft 365 Email/Azure backup solutions.

Pinellas County Government, Clearwater, FL.

County Government serving the needs of the public

2013 - 2017

CHIEF INFORMATION OFFICER

Appointed by eleven members of the Business Technology Services (BTS) Board. BTS is the center of enterprise technology leadership throughout Pinellas County Government. Re-organize and direct all aspects of Information Technology including Infrastructure Engineering, Security, Application Development and Support, Operations, Project Management Office, Customer Relationship Management, Finance and Budgets. BTS supported the Board of County Commissioners including County Administration and the following Constitutionals Offices; Property Appraiser, Tax Collector, Supervisor of Elections, Clerk of the Circuit Court, Sheriff and the Sixth Circuit Court of Florida; Courts, State Attorney and Public Defender.

- Provide an individual 5 year technology strategic plan which aligns with each board member's mission and strategic plan.
- Increase staff and process efficiencies by partnering with the Sixth Circuit Court members to implement a new integrated Criminal Justice module for the Sixth Circuit Justice Consolidated Case Management System.
- Enable user efficiencies and enriched experience through additional functionality of the Oracle Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) system for all modules including Finance, Accounting, Procurement, Payroll and Human Resources.
- Enhance Government transparency by implementing an award winning citizen Business Intelligence portal.
- Decrease security risk 3X by implementing a new Advanced Security Methodology including a Security Operations Center.
- Adopt Amazon Web Services for Disaster Recovery and implement Microsoft 365 Email/Azure solutions.
- Improve the County wide ESRI GIS infrastructure and governance winning the ESRI's Enterprise GIS award.

Connecticut State Government, Hartford, CT.

2004 - 2013

Department of Education

State of CT Agency serving the educational needs of CT students

CHIEF INFORMATION OFFICER

Recruited to provide the needed leadership, vision and development of IT strategies and solutions needed to align with the agency's executive team, state legislators and Governor's Education initiatives. Drive innovation through change across a highly skilled team of technology professionals supporting Application Development and support, Infrastructure Engineering, Operations, Governance, Project Management Office, Customer Relations Management, Finance and Budgets.

- Enhance statewide strategic education planning by partnering with 200 school districts and 1200 schools on and approving the state's five year educational technology plan for 560,000 Students and 72,000 Teachers and Administrators.
- Increase student technology by 30% through the deployment of new computers and infrastructure to 11,000 students, 3500 adult students and 1400 teachers and administrators across the agencies 18 Technical High School Campuses.
- Improve student reporting by 25% though the enhancement of the state's Public School Information System and implementing a School Interoperability Framework to automate the student data collection process.
- Complete a regulatory statewide engineering of a large scale computer and network infrastructure readiness initiative for 1200 schools to meet the requirements of the Smarter Balanced online assessment testing system.

Department of Transportation

State of CT Agency serving the transportation needs of CT travelers

CHIEF INFORMATION OFFICER

Promoted to turn around a legacy based IT organization in order to support new technology initiatives needed to drive a new business model. Recognize organizational improvements through the restructuring of technology professionals across all technology silos including Infrastructure Engineering, Application Development, Project Management Office, Operations, Governance and Customer Relationship Management..

- Recognize a cost decrease of \$2M per year by migrating legacy Mainframe applications to distributive systems; and consolidate common applications into a new work order system.
- Improve state accounting by migrating legacy system financial, human resource and procurement systems and data to the state's centralized Oracle PeopleSoft Enterprise Resource Planning system.
- Improve travelers experience in efficiently navigating road disruptions by deploying a new transportation portal integrated with statewide cameras.
- Decrease yearly cost by \$1M and improve efficiency by enabling external engineering firms to submit road construction documentation electronically through a Cloud Based document management and project approval system.

Department of Information Technology

State of CT Agency serving the enterprise technology needs of all state agencies

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY DIRECTOR

Selected to centralize operational technology teams consisting of Application Hosting, Middleware Support, Database Management, Windows and UNIX Server Engineering teams to support the building of a new centralized state Platform-as-a-Service (PAAS) and Software-as-a-Service (SAAS) model for all state agency applications and enterprise wide applications.

- Increase efficiencies and reduce cost by centralizing government applications to support state agencies including Revenue Services, Education, Transportation, Public Health, Public Safety, Motor Vehicles, Public Works, Emergency Management, Criminal Justice, Environmental Protection, Administrative Services, State Comptrollers, and Policy and Management.
- Improve agencies projected cost and improve efficiency by creating a five year strategic network and systems infrastructure plan aligned to the agencies strategic plan and the state's new E-Government initiatives.
- Recognize operational cost efficiencies by decreasing overall service cost by more than 40% through enterprise level virtualization, server and application consolidation and leveraging shared licensing environments
- Reduce operational cost by 30% by eliminating inefficient redundancy for licensing and support needs across many state agencies by building a centralized E-Licensing portal with associated E-Payment functionality.

Affinion Group, Trumbull, CT

1997 - 2004

International provider of consumer marketing based service products.

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY DIRECTOR

Retained as a turnaround change agent charged with the assessment, organizing and staffing of five infrastructure engineering departments in the delivery of quality technology operations to meet the business need for a brick and mortar and ecommerce based online compliment for a large scale direct marketing and hospitality operation. Acting Vice President of IT Operations overseeing the activity of 130 staff.

- Improve business unit operations by 2X through the building of a centralized enterprise business solution integrating a legacy financial and accounting system, several reservation and loyalty applications and suite of large scale web portals
- Facilitate a corporate restructure through the consolidation of technology systems, support staff and remote facilitates supporting multiple online travel and hospitality business system to a newly formed business travel unit
- Increase company cash flow position by 10% by improving the monthly interest positions through the building of a high performance, high-availability EFT/EDI system for reliable bank transfers of credit card processing files
- Recognize a 10X increase in customer call capacity by completing the technology build out of ten large scale customer contact facilities across North America totaling 2M square feet and \$40M of technology cost.

International Business Machines, East Fishkill, NY

1987 - 1997

International semiconductor manufacturing division.

SENIOR SYSTEMS ANALYST

Promoted to provide Lead Engineering support for semi-conductor manufacturing lithography systems, associated software systems and manufacturing related processes within four large manufacturing facilities. Programming Leader who created innovative software programs to meet quality standards used within all levels of lithography process manufacturing.

- Develop software programs, program scripts and applications used in post manufacturing processing to determine parameters of layered semiconductor substrates increasing overall product yields by 15%.
- Increase manufacturing capacity by 50% by managing the build out of several new large scale lithography system manufacturing areas totaling 200,000 square feet along with associated quality based processes.
- Increase overall quality performance by providing the program direction regarding the creation of a new six sigma quality standards based off new technology capabilities for lithography pattern placement and subsequent substrate alignment

EDUCATION

Masters of Business Administration (MBA) - John F. Welch College of Business, Sacred Heart University, Fairfield, CT

Bachelors of Arts (BA), Computer Science - Mount Saint Mary College, Newburgh, NY

AWARDS

2016 ESRI Enterprise Award - One ESRI customer worldwide for innovated use of Geographic Information Systems

2013-2017 Public Technology Institute Awards - Consecutive years for Community Engagement, Tech Savvy and Technology Solutions

PREVIOUS BOARDS AND COMMITTEES

Pinellas County Government

Chair, Technology Steering Cooperative Member, Business Technology Service Board Member, Pinellas County Human Rights Board Member, Criminal Justice Information Board Member. Oracle Business Application Committee

State Of Connecticut

Co-Chair, Agency Data Governance Committee Member, Connecticut Educators Technology Association Member, Governors Commission of Education Technology Member, Governors Red Tape and Removal Task Force Member, State Agencies CIO Round Table